Register of the Guy Jean Pauker Papers, 1928-1996
Hoover Institution Archives
Guy Jean Pauker Papers,
1928-1996
82096
Pauker, Guy J.
271 manuscript boxes, 34 card file boxes, 1 oversize box, 5 envelopes, 10 slide boxes, 35 microfilm reels, 1 motion picture film reel (146 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Studies, reports, memoranda, notes, correspondence, trial transcripts, bulletins, press summaries, clippings, and printed matter, relating to political, social, and economic conditions in Indonesia; Indonesian foreign relations, especially with the United States; communism in Indonesia; the coup of 1965 in Indonesia, and trials in its aftermath; and education in Indonesia.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1982.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Studies, reports, memoranda, notes, correspondence, trial transcripts, bulletins, press summaries, clippings, and printed matter, relating to political, social, and economic conditions in Indonesia; Indonesian foreign relations, especially with the United States; communism in Indonesia; the coup of 1965 in Indonesia, and trials in its aftermath; and education in Indonesia.
Access Points
Indonesia.; Indonesia--Politics and government--1950-1966.; Indonesia--Politics and government--1966-; Indonesia--History--Coup d'etat, 1965.; Indonesia--Economic conditions--1945-; Indonesia--Social conditions.; Indonesia--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Foreign relations--Indonesia.; Communism--Indonesia.; Education--Indonesia.; Communism.; Education.; United States--Foreign relations.; Moving-pictures.; Slides (Photography)
Biography
American political scientist; senior staff member, Rand Corporation, 1960-
Biographical Note
1916, September 15 born, Bucharest, Rumania
1938 Lic es lett, University of Bucharest
1939 Lic en droit, University of Bucharest
1950 AM, Harvard University
1952 Ph.D., Harvard University
1954-55 Postdoctoral Ford Fellowship in Indonesia
1952-56 Instructor and lecturer, Harvard University
1953-56 Research associate, Massachussetts Institute of Technology
1955 co-author, Comparative Politics of Non-Western Countries
1956-59 Assistant professor, political science, University of California, Berkeley
1958 author, Indonesian Images of Their National Self
1959 author, Southeast Asia As a Problem Area in the Next Decade
1959-1963 Associate professor, political science, University of California, Berkeley
1960- Senior staff member, Rand Corporations, Social Science Department
1962 contributor, The Role of the Military in Indonesia
1970- Research associate, Environmental Quality Lab, California, Institute of Technology
1972 co-author, Smog: A Report to the Peoples
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1947-1973 (Box 1-2)
  Correspondence arranged alphabetically by last name of correspondent.
  - Abdulgani, Roeslan, 1960 (Box 1., Folder 1)
  - Aikin, Charles, 1957 (Folder 2)
  - Alisjahbana, S. Takdir, 1958 (Folder 3)
  - Allen, Raymond, 1959 (Folder 4)
  - Asia Foundation, The, 1960 (Folder 5)
  - Benda, Harry J., 1959 (Folder 6)
  - Brackman, Arnold C., 1967 (Folder 7)
  - Dang Duc Khoi, n.d. (Folder 8)
  - Davies, Joss, 1964 (Folder 9)
  - Dougharty, Larry, 1971 (Folder 10)
  - El Ibrahimy, Nur, 1959 (Folder 11)
  - Feith, Herbert, 1972 (Folder 12)
  - Gailbraith, Francis J., 1953 (Folder 13)
  - Geisler, Richard A., 1960 (Folder 14)
  - Gie, Goei Hok, 1958 (Folder 15)
  - Glassburner, Bruce, 1961 (Folder 16)
  - Goss, Hilton P., 1959 (Folder 17)
  - Gould, James W., 1957 (Folder 18)
  - Harvard University, Graduate School of Public Administration, Defense Studies Program, 1961 (Folder 19)
  - Hawkins, Everett D., 1954 (Folder 20)
  - Heath, James P., 1959 (Folder 21)
  - Hnatko, Florence A., 1972 (Folder 22)
  - Howland, Richard C., 1968 (Folder 23)
  - Indonesia
    - Dewan National, 1958 (Folder 24)
    - Ministry of Information, 1958 (Folder 25)
  - Kahin, George, 1958 (Folder 26)
  - Karam, Frank, 1961 (Folder 27)
  - Karnow, Stanley, 1966 (Folder 28)
  - Kelley, Baiba, 1966 (Folder 29)
  - Kie, Lim Bian, 1972 (Folder 30)
  - Kissinger, Henry A., 1959 (Folder 31)
  - Koesnan, Rh., 1959 (Folder 32)
  - Kohlberg, Alfred, 1947-49, 1955-56 (Folder 33)
  - Landry, Lionel, 1973 (Folder 34)
  - Langer, Paul F., 1959 (Folder 35)
  - Library of Congress, 1954 (Folder 36)
  - Lilienthal, Philip, 1961 (Folder 37)
  - Lyon, Peter, 1966 (Folder 38)
  - Martin, June M., 1956 (Folder 39)
  - Martin, Pierre, 1968 (Folder 40)
  - Miller, Paul, 1959 (Folder 41)
  - Mintz, Jeanne S., 1954 (Folder 42)
  - Moh, Danny, 1960 (Folder 42A)
  - Molenaar, E., 1954 (Folder 43)
  - Nishijima, Shigetada, 1958 (Folder 44)
  - Oliver, Douglas L., 1954 (Folder 45)
  - O'Neill, Thomas P., 1955 (Folder 46)
  - Palmier, Leslie H., 1956 (Folder 47)
  - Pembangunan, Ltd., 1958-59 (Folder 48)
  - Pirngadie, Rudy, 1958 (Folder 49)
  - Polamka, Peter, 1968 (Folder 50)
  - Rasjid, S. M., 1958 (Folder 51)
  - Rogers, W. S., 1954 (Folder 52)
  - Rosecrance, Richard N., 1964 (Folder 53)
  - Sadli, Mohammad, 1960 (Folder 54)
  - Scalapino, Robert A., 1968 (Folder 55)
  - Semadi, Pudjo, 1957 (Folder 56)
  - Simatupang, T. B., 1959-1966 (Folder 57)
  - Smythe, Dallas W., 1968 (Folder 58)
  - Soedjatmoko, 1959 (Folder 59)
  - Soemanto, 1970 (Folder 60)
  - Soemarsono, Soemarso, 1969 (Folder 61)
  - Soetomo, R., 1960 (Folder 62)
  - Sudarmadi, 1970 (Folder 63)
  - Sumarjo, R., 1956 (Folder 64)
  - Taylor, Paul, 1958-59 (Folder 65)
  - Thajeb, Sjarif, 1971 (Folder 66)
  - Thomas, K. D., 1965 (Folder 67)
  - Thurnherr, Charlotte M., 1953 (Folder 68)
  - Tovar, B. Hugh, 1966 (Folder 69)
  - Town Hall, Los Angeles, 1966 (Folder 70)
  - U.S. Department of State. Office of Intelligence Research. External Research Staff. 1954 (Folder 71)
  - University of Indonesia, Library Faculty of Economics, 1959 (Folder 72)
  - Van Niel, Robert, 1954 (Folder 73)
  - Widjajaamiarsa, Kabullah, 1962 (Box 2., Folder 1)
  - Williams, Lea, 1953 (Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 3)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1954-1973 (Box 2-3)
  Drafts, notes, printed and typewritten copies of speeches and writings, arranged alphabetically by subject or title.
  - Comments on and excerpts from published sources, n.d., Typescripts and holographs. (Box 2., Folder 4)
  - Communist Prospects in Indonesia., Typescript (printed copy).
    - May 1964 (Folder 5)
    - November 1964 (Folder 6)
  - Council on Foreign Relations meetings, April 15, 1964, notes on., Typescript (mimeographed copy) and holograph. (Folder 7)
  - Election law in Indonesia, n.d. Untitled drafts and notes. (Folder 8)
  - Indonesia.
    - Indonesia: The PKI's Road to Power, Printed copy. (Folder 9)
    - Untitled drafts and notes pertaining, n.d. (Folder 10-13)
  - Indonesian economic stabilization, 1954, notes on, n.d. (Box 3., Folder 1)
  - The Indonesian Image of the National Self, March 23, 1959., Typescript (mimeographed copy). (Folder 2)
  - Indonesian Image of National Self Project, 1957-59., Handwritten notes. (Folder 3)
  - Indonesian Perspectives on the Indian Ocean, March 1971., Typescript (photocopy). (Folder 4)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Center for International Studies, Project on the Economic and Political Development of Indonesia, notes on, n.d. (Folder 5)
  - The Miracle of Indonesia, January 1, 1973., Printed copy. (Folder 6)
  - 1956 Perspectives on Indonesian Politics and Economic Development, June 26, 1956., Typescript (mimeographed copy). (Folder 7)
  - North Sumatra population, notes on, November 1954 (Folder 8)
  - Pauker Shows Reversal in Asia, Indonesia, Strategic Balances, remarks by G. Pauker, March 22, 1966., Printed copy. (Folder 9)
  - Political Aspects of Economic Development, n.d.
    - Handwritten draft (Folder 10)
    - Typescript (Folder 11)
  - The Problem of Political Stability, n.d., Handwritten draft. (Folder 12)
  - The Role of the Military in Indonesia, n.d., Handwritten and typewritten drafts. (Folder 13)
  - Tentara Nasional Indonesia (Indonesian National Army) by A. H. Nasution, comments on, n.d., Holograph. (Folder 14)
  - Untitled drafts and notes (Folder 15)
- COMMUNIST PARTY OF INDONESIA (PARTAI KOMMUNIS INDONESIA), 1955-1971. (Box 3-6)
  Correspondence, reports, minutes of meetings, manuscripts and other materials issued by and pertaining to the Indonesian Communist Party.
  - General (Box 3., Folder 16-18)
  - General (Box 4., Folder 1)
  - Aidit, Dipa Nusantra
    - General (Folder 2)
    - Anti-Imperialisme Dans Front Nasional, 1962 (Folder 3)
    - The International Communist Movement and the Southeast Asian Revolution, October 3, 1963 (Folder 4)
    - Lessons From the History of the Indonesian Communist Party, speech, May 23, 1960 (Folder 5)
    - Pilihan Tulisan, 1965 (Folder 6-8)
    - Political Report, May 1965 (Folder 9)
    - Report to the Central Committee of the Communist Party of Indonesia, February 10-12, 1963 (Folder 10)
    - The Selected Works of D. N. Aidit, September 1961 (Folder 11)
    - The Selected Works of D. N. Aidit, September 1961 (Box 5., Folder 1)
    - The Selected Works of D. N. Aidit, Volume I (Folder 2-3)
  - Antonov, I., In the Struggle For the People's Interests: On the 47th Anniversary of the Communist Party of Indonesia, article, Pravda, May 28, 1967 (Folder 4)
  - Appeal of the Marxist-Leninist Group of the CP of Indonesia, November 1967 (Folder 5)
  - Articles on the leaders of the Indonesian Communist Party, September 1965 (Folder 6)
  - Australian Communist Party, joint statement with, December 28, 1959 (Folder 7)
  - Central Committee
    - General Report for the Sixth National Congress, February 1959 (Folder 8)
    - Political Bureau
      - An Evaluation of the Kerdja Cabinet, After One Year in Office, July 8, 1960 (Folder 9)
      - Report to the Seventh Expanded Plenary Session, November 19, 1958 (Folder 9A)
      - Statements, 1966
        - August 16 (Folder 10)
        - August 17 (Folder 11)
    - A Political Report by the Chairman, 3rd Session, 1961 (Folder 12)
    - Second Plenary Session, December 1960 (Folder 13)
    - Second Plenum
      - Resolutions, January 1964 (Folder 14)
      - Speeches, January 1964 (Folder 15)
    - Fourth Plenum, decisions, April 1962 (Folder 16)
    - Sixth Plenum, documents, March-April 1958 (Folder 17)
    - Eighth Plenum, August 6-7, 1959 (Box 6., Folder 1)
  - Constitution, 1959 (Folder 2)
  - Fortieth anniversary of the Indonesian Communist Party, May 1960 (Folder 3)
  - Four Year Plan (Folder 4)
  - Fu, Hsiung, The Indonesian People's Revolutionary Struggle and the Indonesian Communist Party, article, Peking Review, No. 23, June 1963 (Folder 5)
  - Hindley, Donald, The PKI and the Peasants, article, Problems of Communism, November-December 1962 (Folder 6)
  - Indonesian Communist Subversion From Abroad, article, Asian Notes, January 13, 1969 (Folder 7)
  - Indonesian Communists Diagree Over Party's Future Role, article, Asian Notes, May 1, 1967 (Folder 8)
  - Kepidupan Partai (Party Life), selections from, June 1960 (Folder 9)
  - NASAKOM Cabinet, 1964 (Folder 10)
  - Pajetta, Giuliano, Italian Communists Praise Performance of Indonesian Communist Party, January 1964 (Folder 11)
  - Program revision, September 1959 (Folder 12)
  - Sixth National Congress, August 6-7, 1959
    - Foreign Fraternal Delegations (Folder 13)
    - Speeches (Folder 14)
  - Starner, Frances L., The Partai Kommunis Indonesia, n.d. (Folder 15)
  - United Moslem Party Demands dissolution of PKI, September 1960 (Folder 16)
  - Van Der Kroef, Justus M.17 Dilemnas of Indonesian Communism, article, Pacific Affairs, Vol. XXXV, No. 2, Summer 1962
    - How Dear Is the Indonesian Communist Party? 1965 (Folder 18)
    - Indonesian Communism Under Aidit, article, Problems of Communism, November-December 1958 (Folder 19)
- INDONESIA SUBJECT FILE, 1945-1980. (Box 6-62)
  Correspondence, reports, memoranda, government documents, clippings, printed matter, and other materials, pertaining to or issued by the Indonesian government.
  - General (Box 6, Folder 20-21)
  - Abdulgani, Roeslan
    - Exposition of the motives of conferring the degree of Doctor Honoris Causa in Political Science, University of Padjadjaran, July 31, 1961 (Folder 22)
    - The Political Party System of Indonesia On the Eve of the Elections, paper read before the Mata Hari Club, Djakarta, September 21, 1955 (Folder 23)
    - Politics and Science, speech, Padjadjaran University, July 31, 1961 (Folder 24)
    - Recent Poltical Changes in Indonesia, speech, Yale University, December 9, 1966 (Box 7., Folder 1)
    - Statement on the restoration of the lawful rights of the People's Republic of China in the United Nations, November 28, 1966 (Folder 2)
  - Aerial survey, 1955 (Folder 3)
  - Agriculture and land use (Folder 4)
  - Air transport services agreement with the U.S., January 1968 (Folder 5)
  - Alisjahbana, S. Takdir, The Promotion of Understanding Among People, November 1969 (Folder 6)
  - The Ambonese Revolt, n.d. (Folder 7)
  - American community in Djakarta, telephone directory, n.d. (Folder 8)
  - American University, Washington, D.C., Special Operations Research Office, Indonesia Project, 1960 (Folder 9)
  - American Universities Field Staff Reports Service, 1957-59 (Folder 10)
  - Antara News Bulletin, 1967-1973 (Folder 11)
  - Armed forces
    - General (Folder 12-14)
    - The Armed Forces and the Maintenance of Stability in Indonesia - With Specific Refence to U.S. Assistance, July 1973 (Folder 15)
    - Anti-Corruption Act, April-September 1957 (Box 8., Folder 1)
    - Army after October 17th affair (Folder 2)
    - Army and the press, 1957 (Folder 3)
    - Army policy, 1957 (Folder 4)
    - Clippings
      - 1953-56 (Folder 5)
      - 1955 (Folder 6-7)
      - 1955 (Box 9., Folder 1)
    - Djakarta military
      - 1953-54 (Folder 2)
      - 1955 (Folder 3)
      - 1956 (Folder 4-6)
      - 1956-57 (Folder 7)
      - 1957 (Folder 8)
      - 1957 (Box 10., Folder 1-2)
      - General (Folder 3-4)
      - ACS (Folder 5)
      - ACS and the press, 1956 (Folder 6)
      - ACS policy on the Army, 1956 (Folder 7)
      - Army and the National Conference, 1957 (Folder 8)
      - Army vs. the press (Folder 9)
      - Clippings
        - 1956-57 (Box 11., Folder 1-3)
        - 1957 (Folder 4-6)
      - Corruption, 1956 (Folder 7)
      - Foreign project and military mission, 1956 (Folder 8)
      - Kabinet B.H. (Box 12., Folder 1)
      - KSAD (Folder 1A)
      - Lubis affair, 1957 (Folder 2)
      - Nasution's period, November-December 1955 (Folder 3)
      - Palembang Conference, January-February 1957 (Folder 4)
      - Promotion, reconstruction of the Army, 1956 (Folder 5)
      - Simbolon affairs (Folder 6)
      - Sulindo (Folder 7)
    - Djakarta military command, 1956 (Folder 8)
    - General condition of the Army during the second half of 1956 and ACS policy (Folder 9)
    - Hatta, Mohammad, Movement of the Dewan Banteng..., June 1957 (Folder 10)
    - Kalimantan policy, 1957 (Folder 11)
    - Military Administration Conference, June 1957 (Folder 12)
    - Military Command, 1957 (Folder 13)
    - Military Mission and Foreign Project, 1957 (Folder 14)
    - Nasution, Abdul Haris, Notes On Indonesian Military Policy, May 1955 (Box 13., Folder 1-3)
    - Nasution, Basarudin, Explanations On Some Paragraphs of the Regeling SOB Regulations, 1957 (Folder 4)
    - Siliwangi Division (Folder 5)
    - Sokowati, S.
      - Application of the Development of All-People Defense to the Realization of New Order, Pantja-Sila, November 24, 1964 (Folder 6)
      - Indonesian Revolution Gives Mental Strength, November 30, 1964 (Folder 7)
      - Questions and proposals by attendants of the Revolution Cadres Course on a lecture by, November 24, 1964 (Folder 8)
    - Sulawesi policy (Folder 9)
    - Sumatra policy (Box 14., Folder 1)
  - Arrested VIP in TT III and general security problem (Folder 2)
  - Art, culture, dance (Folder 3-4)
  - Atomic energy (Folder 5)
  - Badan Penjelidek Usaha Persiapan Kemerdekaan Indonesia (Investigating Committee for Preparation of Indonesia's Independence), The Territory of Indonesian State, discussions, Djakarta, 1945 (Folder 6)
  - Bali
    - General (Folder 7)
    - Geertz, Clifford, Form and Variation in Balinese Village Structure, November 1958 (Folder 8)
    - Geertz, Clifford and Hildred, The Balinese Kinship System, January 1959 (Folder 9)
    - Geertz, Hildred, Ethnic vs. National Loyalties in the Indonesian Village: Bali, n.d. (Folder 10)
  - Bank Indonesia, 1956-57 (Folder 11)
  - Bibliographies (Folder 12)
  - Bogor Conference, December 1954 (Folder 13)
  - Books for sale on Indonesia, 1965 (Folder 14)
  - Budget, 1958 (Folder 15)
  - Butwell, Richard, The Impact of Indonesia on the International Relations of Southeast Asia, n.d. (Folder 16)
  - Carr, Denzel, Bahasa Indonesia, 1956 (Folder 17)
  - Central Organization of All-Indonesian Labor (SOBSI), 1960 (Box 15., Folder 1)
  - Centre For Strategic and International Studies, Djakarta, seminars on Indonesia, April 23 - May 12, 1973 (Folder 2)
  - Chinese in (Folder 3)
  - Colbert, Evelyn, Reconsiderations - The Road Not Taken - Decolonization and Independence in Indonesia and Indochina, article, Foreign Affairs, Vol. 51, No. 3, April 1973 (Folder 4)
  - Commerce
    - 1955-57 (Folder 5)
    - Mears, Leon A., Some Aspects of Rice Marketing in Indonesia, August 3, 1958 (Folder 6)
    - Wolters, O. W., Early Indonesian Commerce - A Study of the Origins of Srivijaya, excerpts from (Folder 7)
  - Communism in (Folder 8-11)
  - Communism in (Box 16., Folder 1)
  - Consulate, San Francisco, California
    - General (Folder 2)
    - Information Section, Information on Indonesia, 1958-59 (Folder 3)
    - Information and Trade Bureau, News On Indonesia
      - 1961-62 (Folder 4)
      - 1962 (Folder 5)
      - 1962-63 (Folder 6)
      - 1965 (Folder 7)
      - 1968-1970 (Folder 8)
      - 1970-71 (Folder 9)
      - 1972 (Box 17., Folder 1)
  - Coordination Center for Southeast Asian Studies, Bangkok, Communication Habits in Indenesia, October 1961 (Folder 2)
  - Darmanto, R. M., speech, American Indonesian Chamber of Commerce, New York, January 10, 1952 (Folder 3)
  - Davies, Derek, Indonesia - Consensus in the Negative, Foreign Eastern Economic Review, February 25, 1974 (Folder 4)
  - Department of Education and Culture
    - Education and cultural technical assistance proposals, 1971-72 (Folder 5)
    - Office of Educational Development
      - BPP System Development Tasks - Report of Bernede-Heneveld Mission, February 22 - March 6, 1971 (Folder 6)
      - United Nations Development Program
        - Plan of operation, 1971 (Folder 7)
        - Project Manager's Report, June 9, 1971 (Folder 8)
        - Report of the Review Mission, June 1971 (Folder 9)
    - Request for UNDP/UNESCO Project Ins. 28, July 1971 (Folder 10)
    - Textbook Project - Primary Schools, 1971-74 (Folder 11)
  - Department of Information
    - Art and entertainment activities in the framework of foreign relations, 1971 (Folder 12)
    - Commercial Code and domestic capital investment, 1971 (Folder 13)
    - Criminal acts of corruption, elimination of, 1971 (Folder 14)
    - Elections and voting, 1971 (Folder 15)
    - Facts and Figures, 1971 (Folder 16)
    - Foreign Information Directorate, ASEAN - Report of the Second Meeting of the ASEAN Permanent Committee on Mass Media, Kuala Lampur, May 17-19, 1971 (Folder 17)
    - Foreign resident news agencies in Djakarta, 1971 (Folder 18)
    - Government statements, 1971 (Folder 19)
    - Indonesia, Vol. I, No. 1, 1960 (Folder 20)
    - Information Bulletin, 1971 (Box 18., Folder 1)
    - Jogjakarta, n.d. (Folder 2)
    - Law No. 5 of the Year 1970 on the State Budget for Year 1970-71 (Folder 3)
    - Pakistan, 1971 (Folder 4)
    - Permits to alien vessels in Indonesia's territorial waters, 1971 (Folder 5)
    - President of Indonesia, decision of, No. 3, June 1971 (Folder 6)
    - Sokowati, S., T.N.I. and Civic Mission, An Aspect of Regional Development, 1963 (Folder 7)
    - Tjibinong Cement Factory, granting of additional tax allowances to, July 1971 (Folder 8)
  - Derkach, Nadia, The Soviet Policy Towards Indonesia On the West Irian and the Malaysian Disputes, March 1965 (Folder 9)
  - Description and travel (Folder 10-11)
  - Devillers, Philippe, L'Indonesie Depuis 1942, reprint, Revue Francaise de Science Politique, Vol. VIII, No. 4, December 1958 (Folder 12)
  - Dewan Lambung Mangkurat (Lambung Mangkurat Council) (Folder 13)
  - Dewan Nasional (National Council) (Folder 14-15)
  - Dewan Perantjang Nasional (National Planning Council) (Folder 16)
  - Djakarta - It's Rehabilitation and Development, n.d. (Folder 17)
  - Djakarta Military Conference, September 16-17, 1959 (Folder 18)
  - Djakarta press excerpts, 1967 (Box 19., Folder 1)
  - Djiwa Baru, 1957-58 (Folder 2)
  - Dutch East Indies
    - General (Folder 3)
    - Bromley, M., A Preliminary Report on Law Among the Grand Valley Dani of Irian Barat, 1965 (Folder 4)
    - Clippings (Folder 5-7)
    - History
      - 1942-45 (Folder 8)
      - 1945-46 (Folder 9)
      - 1946 (Folder 10)
      - 1946-49 (Folder 11)
    - Kerr, J. R., The Political Future of New Guinea, Australian Outlook, reprint, Vol. 13, No. 3, September 1959 (Folder 12)
    - The Nationalization of Dutch Owned Enterprises in (Folder 13)
    - Netherlands Information Bureau, New York
      - The Netherlands Commonwealth and the Future, 1945 (Folder 14)
      - Netherlands News, Vol. 7, June-October 1943 (Folder 15)
    - U.S. Department of State, Work of the United Good Offices Committee in Indonesia, March 14, 1948 (Folder 16)
    - Van Der Kroef, Justus M., The West New Guinea Dispute, 1958 (Folder 17)
    - Voting Procedures in West Irian, General Elections Institute, Indonesia, 1969 (Folder 18)
  - East Indonesia, security, 1954 (Box 20., Folder 1)
  - Economic conditions
    - General (Folder 2-4)
    - Condliffe, J. B., Private Investment in Indonesia, n.d. (Folder 5)
    - Hensley, Roy J., The Role of Development Banks and Corporations in Economic Development: With An Examination of the Indonesian Experience, n.d. (Folder 6)
    - Higgins, Benjamin
      - Economic Stabilization and Development in Indonesia, Institute of Pacific Relations paper, 1954 (Folder 7)
      - Indonesia's Development Plans and Problems, 1966 (Folder 8)
    - Mears, Leon N., Economic Development in Indonesia, n.d. (Folder 9)
    - Rieffel, Alexis and Aninda S. Wirjasuputra, Goverment Owned Enterprises in Indonesia, US/AID/Indonesia staff paper, January 1972 (Folder 10)
    - Van Der Kroef, Justus M., Indonesia's Economic Dilemna, Far Eastern Survey, Vol. XXIV, No. 4, April 1960 (Folder 11)
  - Editors, journalists, news agencies, publishers, 1970 (Folder 12)
  - Education
    - General (Box 21., Folder 1-5)
    - Allen, Raymond B., Report on the Institutions of Higher Education in Indonesia Emphasizing Organization, Structure, and Management, August 1, 1959 (Folder 6)